“创始吸血鬼”前情提要
ELlJAH: Previously on The Originals...
这座城市曾经是我的家
This town was my home once.
我们的社区正遭受攻击
她们是在向我们宣战
Our community is under attack.
They're declaring war on us.
我因你们的誓言“永远在一起”而死
I die, all because of your vow,
"always and forever."
- 如果你是来报仇的…
- 仇我一定会报
-lf you have come here seeking revenge...
-Oh, I'll have my revenge.
- 我叫杰克森
- 你就是那头一直看着我的狼
-I'm Jackson.
-You're the wolf who's been watching me.
马赛尔叫女巫给我们下了咒
Marcel had us cursed by a witch.
- 我们得好好聊一下了
- 你是我的家人
-You and I are gonna have a chat.
-You're my family.
我哥哥以为我
一如过去千年般忠心于他
REBEKAH: My brother expects
My loyalty as he has for 1,000 years.
克劳斯永远不会停止控制你
Klaus will never stop
trying to control you.
他这一生只真正害怕过一个人
All his life, there's only ever been
one man he has truly feared.
我的父亲麦可
My father, Mikael.
我们只需要一个能帮我们找到他的女巫
All we need is a witch
who can help us find him.
这就是我复仇的方式
让你看看她的背叛
That's how I'll have my revenge,
by showing you her betrayal.
召唤麦可是我的主意
It was my idea to summon Mikael.
你们俩尽快逃走吧，越远越好
Both of you, run as far
and as fast as you can.
(1919年 纽奥良）
这真是头一遭
Well, this is a first.
狼人、吸血鬼、女巫，还有腐败的警察
Werewolves, vampires,
witches and dirty cops...
都齐聚一堂，举杯狂欢
...all happy as clams
and drunk as stoats.
- 这真是个迷人的城市
- 敬禁酒时期
-You got to love this city.
-To a new era.
带来的新一轮合作
Collaboration
in the face of prohibition.
敬你们的码头、他们的私酒
还有我们用来藏酒的剧院
To your docks, their booze
and our theaters to hide it under.
不客气，先生们
You're welcome, boys.
现在我得想个更合适的方式
再私下好好谢一谢
Now, I shall have to think of a way
to thank you personally
你这位狼人女王
in a manner befitting
a werewolf queen.
我在舞池等你
Catch you on the dance floor.
真没想到会有今天啊
Who would have thought it possible...
我们终于统一纽奥良了
...the unification of New Orleans?
我们做到了，哥哥
We did it, brother.
当然了，都是我们共同努力的结果
尼克劳斯，但眼前的这一切…
Certainly, we worked together, Niklaus.
But this vision?
都拜你所赐
This was all you.
这一切都拜你所赐
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）
剧名：恐怖戏码
卡蜜儿
主演：约瑟夫摩根
Camille.
到这来
Please.
主演：丹尼尔吉利斯
你找我什么事？
Why did you call me?
你找到救我叔叔的办法了吗？
You found a way to help my uncle?
我尽力，但现在，我需要你的帮忙
主演：克莱儿荷特
I can try.
But first, I need your help.
我没时间跟你玩游戏，以利亚
I don't have time for games, Elijah.
他身上的诅咒越来越严重了
主演：菲比托金
The hex on him
is getting worse by the day.
我弟弟胸口里正插着一把神秘的匕首
主演：查尔斯麦可戴维斯
My brother has a mystical
torture device buried in his chest.
而他孩子的母亲如今也下落不明
And the mother of his child
is inexplicably missing.
所以我向你保证
主演：莉雅派普斯
So, I can assure you,
我也没时间跟你玩什么游戏
主演：莉雅派普斯
I have no time
to play any games, either.
主演：丹妮儿坎贝尔
你要我做什么？
What do you need me to do?
女巫给我的匕首正插在他体内吗？
The dagger the witch gave me
is inside of him?
那东西停留在他体内多一秒
他就多痛苦一分
And every second it remains
causes Niklaus untold suffering.
- 这是谁干的？
- 是我
-Who stabbed him?
-I did.
现在我准备把它取出来
你最好站远一点
And now I intend to remove it.
You might wanna take a step back.
为什么要我来这？
Why am I here?
因为所有能来的人当中
Because of all the people
that could be here.
你可能是唯一一个
他不会立刻杀掉的人
You're probably the only one
he wouldn't immediately slaughter.
还有，每当他提到你时
他的语气里…
Also, he speaks of you with...
总带着罕有的尊敬
what is a rare degree,
for him at least, of respect.
我想大概是你让他重新认识了自己
You see, you challenge him
to see himself
和周遭的人
and others in a new light!
很快我的这项技能就会派上用场
A wonderful skill that I shall be
counting on very shortly.
要知道，在完全恢复之前
尼克劳斯会很虚弱
You see, Niklaus will be weak
as he recovers.
所以照顾好他，必要时喂他你的血
制片：克里斯多福贺利尔
So watch over him
and feed him if you would.
但别太急，用手腕就好
But slowly, please,
and from your wrist.
你们不是存了很多血袋吗？
Don't you guys have bags of blood
in storage?
没错，但你的血里有马鞭草
制片：兰斯安德森
We do, but your blood is laced
with vervain.
这会灼伤他，能让他喝得慢点
So it will burn him.
He'll ingest it slower.
或许你可以好好利用这段时间
Perhaps, you could use the time
constructively,
说服他不要杀了自己的妹妹
persuade him
not to murder his baby sister.
尼克劳斯
Niklaus.
我无意让你如此痛苦
It was not my desire
to bring you pain,
但我不会眼睁睁看着你伤害蕾贝卡
but I will not see you hurt Rebekah.
我担心莎宾
正在谋划对我们的最后一击
Now, I fear Sabine may be making
a final move against us.
我要找到她并结束这一切
I intend to find her and to end this.
以利亚
(WEAKLY): Elijah...
你会为此付出代价的
You will pay for this.
这算什么，报复吗？
制片：邦妮怀斯
So, what's this, payback?
听着，我很抱歉骗了你们
我的目标不是你们
Look, I'm sorry I tricked you.
I wasn't after you.
这么说，我们只是附带伤害了？
What?
We were just collateral damage?
你差点让她和杰克森
在那场种植园大火中丧命
You almost burned her and Jackson
alive in that plantation fire.
小心点，莎宾
Careful, Sabine!
还是莎莉丝特，你爱叫什么都行
Or Celeste, or whatever
you like to call yourself.
你突然的举动会让我不安
有想杀人的冲动
Sudden moves make me jumpy,
and homicidal.
- 怎么，你要杀了我吗，亲爱的？
- 不，我有更好的主意
-What, you're gonna kill me, honey?
-No, I know better.
我知道关于你的一切
See, I know all about you.
我知道你喜欢自我了断
然后再附身到另一副身体上
I know that you like to off yourself
and jump into other people's bodies.
这次你休想这么做
Well, that's not gonna happen here.
我知道我杀不了你
I know I can't kill you.
但你要想对我下咒
我这位朋友伊芙会给你膝盖来一枪
But try hexing me, and my friend,
Eve, here will kneecap you.
你对她出手，我就会让你非常痛苦
Go for her, and then,
well, I'll really make it hurt.
你究竟想怎么样？
So, what do you want?
90年代时
In the '90s,
你占有了一个女巫的身体
编剧：戴克兰迪巴拉，黛安艾德穆强
you inhabited a witch
她叫布琳德弗罗
编剧：戴克兰迪巴拉，黛安艾德穆强
named Brynne Deveraux,
还记得吗？
remember?
马赛尔要她，也就是你
Marcel had her, you,
对一群狼人施咒
导演：克里斯葛瑞斯莫
put a curse on a lot of werewolves
使他们只能在月圆之夜
导演：克里斯葛瑞斯莫
so they'd only turn human
才能变身为人
on a full moon.
我懂了
I see.
就是我干的
你想报仇是吗？
Yes, that was me.
And let me guess. You want revenge.
我要你解除诅咒
I want you to undo the curse.
我从没想过我会做这样的事
Things I never thought I'd be doing:
给一个吸血鬼喂血
feeding a vampire.
16岁的我一定会觉得这事酷毙了
My 16-year-old self would think
I'm really cool right now.
慢点好吗？
(CRUNCHES)
Ah, slow down.
你喝到马鞭草不会难受吗？
Doesn't the vervain burn?
你现在应该懂了，卡蜜
As you may have yet to realize,
Cami,
带给我们痛苦的东西
和给我们能量的东西
the line between what brings us pain
and what sustains us
界限并不是很鲜明
is far thinner than one imagines.
你是在说我的血
Are we talking about my blood
还是在说你内心
追杀最爱之人的需求？
or your need to hunt down
the people you love most?
我现在很虚弱，听不了你的说教
I'm too weak
for one of your talks right now.
她是你妹妹，你怎么会恨她？
She's your sister.
How can you hate her?
因为她对我做了一件
Because she has done
一千年来没有人能做到的事
what no one else has managed
to do to me for a thousand years.
伤透我的心
Rip my heart out.
看看那两个人
Look at these two,
明明是情侣
还假装不在一起
pretending to be apart
while so clearly a pair.
尼克劳斯，别这样
你干嘛非得找麻烦？
Niklaus, not now.
Why must you cause trouble?
我想借这个机会
I'd like to take this opportunity
让大家关注一下这两个人
to draw attention to two people...
他们一直背着我偷偷摸摸在一起
...who have been sneaking around
behind my back together.
我们进入了新的时代
As we move into a new era,
所以需要更先进的态度
we require more progressive
attitudes to match.
这一杯…
So....
敬我亲爱的妹妹
To my loving sister
以及我的左右手
亦是我的挚友，马赛尔
and my right-hand man
and best friend, Marcel.
愿他们获得幸福
May they find joy in each other.
说够了，音乐继续
Enough talk. Music!
这么多年来
Over the years,
我阻档你的情路
只是为了保护你
I've thwarted your loves
simply to protect you.
我知道如果我们再次逃亡
你一定会为爱而心碎
I knew if we had to run again,
your heart would be broken.
但我们不用再逃亡了
But we don't have to run anymore.
我们找到了家
We've found a home.
祝你幸福，妹妹
Be happy, my sister.
我放下了戒心
I'd let my guard down
开始享受幸福
我太愚蠢了
and given in to happiness.
More fool, l.
后来我发现，他们早就背叛了我
Turns out,
they'd already betrayed me...
把我躲避了几世纪的人带来了这里
...and brought to town the one thing
I'd been running from for centuries.
我的父亲
My father.
没错
Yes...
(lNHALES SHARPLY) "Oh."
所以你一直执着于无法完成的复仇
So you're consumed by revenge
you'll never achieve.
以利亚暗示说蕾贝卡和马赛尔
现在可能在任何地方
Elijah implied Rebekah and Marcel
could be anywhere in the world.
这可不一定哦
Oh, I'm not so sure about that.
你能相信我们居然公开地
Can you believe we're sitting
out here in the open?
- 毫无顾忌地坐在这里吗？
- 不能
-Bold as brass?
-No.
感觉就像在天堂
It feels like heaven.
洁妮薇召唤我父亲
You know, it's been over six months
已经有六个多月了，什么事也没有
since Genevieve summoned my father,
and nothing.
她的咒语一定是失灵了
Her spell must have failed.
如果真是这样，我们就躲过一劫了
Hey, if so, we dodged a bullet.
好了
Right.
我要去妇女禁酒协会会议上发表演讲
I am off to speak at the
Women's Temperance Society meeting
让这座城市的妻子们
督促她们的丈夫戒酒
to make sure the wives of this city
urge their husbands not to drink.
你们现在不都在做酒类生意吗？
Aren't you all in the booze biz now?
没错
Yes.
但人总是这样，越被禁止
But the more one tells you
you can't have something,
就越渴望
而且不惜代价
the more you crave it...
at all costs.
他会追杀我们到天涯海角
He'll chase us
to the ends of the earth.
他一定会找到我们
And he'll find us.
没有人能躲一辈子
No one can hide forever.
尤其是躲避一个愤怒的米卡森家的人
Especially not
from an angry Mikaelson.
那我们就继续坚持计划
Then we go through with the plan.
要想永远躲开克劳斯的追杀
只有一个办法
There's only one way we'll truly
be able to hide from Klaus forever.
他们会需要隐身咒
They'll need a cloaking spell.
而这个咒语需要女巫来完成
And for that, they'll need a witch.
黛维娜是唯一的机会
如果我们回去找她…
Davina is our one shot.
If we go back and get her--
- 这样是送死
- 只有这个办法
-It's a suicide mission.
-It's our only hope.
我们让她复活，带她离开，远走高飞
We resurrect her, take her with us,
and get out of town.
她会帮我们躲开克劳斯的追踪
他就找不到我们了
Then she can hide us from Klaus
so he'll never find us.
我们甚至不知道要杀哪个女巫
才能让她复活
We don't even know the right witch
to bring her back.
那就全杀了
Then we'll kill them all.
不过就是杀三个连克劳斯米卡森
都能打倒的女巫，没什么大不了
Just kill the three witches
that brought
the mighty Klaus Mikaelson to his knees.
No big deal.
听我说，如果你不想一辈子提心吊胆
Unless you want to spend eternity
looking over your shoulder,
我们只有一个办法
there's only one thing
that we can do.
他们只有一个地方可去
There's only one place they can go.
家
Home.
一旦秩序恢复
你们族类就不能来这里了
When order is restored,
your kind won't be allowed in here.
幸好时候还没到
Well, fortunately,
that day has not yet come.
我要找到莎宾
I need to find Sabine.
她带走了一个对我很重要的人
I believe she's taken someone
very important to me.
你觉得我会帮你吗？
(SCOFFS)
And you thought I'd help you?
莎宾是我们的人
Sabine is one of us,
一心想让女巫势力崛起
committed to the rise
of the witches.
莎宾只一心想毁灭我的家族
The only thing Sabine is committed
to is the destruction of my family.
这有什么不好吗？
And that would be a bad thing, why?
和你母亲一样
Like your mother,
我母亲也是女巫
法力无边的女巫
my mother was also a witch,
a very powerful witch.
事实上，正因为有我的家族
In fact, because of my family,
她的法力才会在你们的血液里流淌
her power now flows
through your veins.
现在，只要莎宾操纵她身边的人
Now, once Sabine manipulates
those around her,
她就会采用她一贯的手法
she will do
what she has always done.
附到别人身上然后就此消失
She will jump into another body
and disappear.
让你们女巫法力尽失
Leaving your witches powerless.
不会，她和我们有一样的信念
她要助我们恢复法力
No, she has the faith.
She will see our power restored.
有个办法能保障这一切
There's a way of guaranteeing this
我也会保障你和你族人的安全
while also securing the safety
of yourself and your kind.
来，这是我母亲的魔法书里的
Here.
This is from my mother's grimoire.
莎莉丝特用了一个类似的咒语
以完成附身
Celeste used a similar spell
to body jump.
如果莎宾所言属实
当她牺牲自己时
If what Sabine says is true,
when she sacrifices herself,
她的法力就会释放回大地
all of her power
will flow back into the earth.
不过，如果她说谎
并试图占用另一副身体
However, if she has lied
and tries to take another body...
这个咒语就会帮她达成另一种效果
...this spell will deliver her
to a very different destination.
现在就请找到莎宾
Now please... Iocate Sabine.
图德巫父死了
REBEKAH:
Papa Tunde is dead.
现在就剩莎宾、贝丝蒂娜和洁妮薇
That leaves Sabine, Bastianna
and Genevieve.
我们要把她们全杀了
We want to kill them all.
等黛维娜一复活，我们就带她离开
And as soon as Davina rises,
we take her with us.
听着，我们只有一次机会
Look, we have one shot at this.
我知道我们成功的机会渺茫
And I know our chances of success
are sweet bugger all,
但我们得试试
but we've got to do it.
所以拜托了，同是丧家之犬
帮帮我们
So, please,
one stray dog to another, help us.
能逢凶化吉还能侃侃而谈
英雄事迹的人可不多
Not many go up against those odds
and live to tell the story.
你有过吗？
Have you?
我还站在这里不是吗？
I'm still standing here, aren't l?
最凶险的我都经历过了
I've gone up
against the worst of them all.
再来一杯
I'll take another.
你很有福气
You're a lucky man.
男人都在寻觅像她这样的女人
Men search the world over
for a woman like her.
她名花有主了，朋友
Well, she's taken, friend.
看得出来
Oh, I can see that.
只是她让我想起了我亡妻年轻时的样子
She reminds me so much
of my departed wife as a girl.
瞧我四处漂泊了这么久
See, I've been traveling
for such a long time,
却在千里之外遇见如此相似的人
真是一种恩赐啊
that it's a blessing to see
a familiar soul so far from home.
对您失去至亲深表遗憾
I'm sorry for your loss.
这是敬那些异乡的故人
Here's to old faces in new places.
我来纽奥良有一天了
我觉得这地方很令人惊喜
I've been in New Orleans for a day,
and I find it to be quite surprising.
要是我知道它和这里的人如此有魅力
Had I known of its charm
and fascinating denizens,
我早就来了
I would have come ages ago.
我想我该谢谢你
此番邀请
I suppose I have to thank you
for extending this invitation.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你是聪明人
Oh, you're a smart man.
你应该知道我是谁
I think you know.
（歌剧爱好者与资助者）
我也是聪明人，所以坐下吧
I'm an intelligent man myself,
so have a seat.
跟你说说今天下午我对你有哪些了解
Let me tell you what I learned
about you this afternoon,
马赛尔杰拉德
Marcel Gerard.
你苦恼受我儿子尼克劳斯的控制
You chafe under the control
of my son, Niklaus,
你愿不惜一切来摆脱他
and would do just about anything
to get rid of him.
甚至是召唤这世上比你还要恨他的人
Even call the one man on this earth
who hates him more than you do.
但我不明白你想得到什么
But I couldn't understand
what you hoped to gain.
这座城市的统治权吗？
Rule of this city?
如我所说，纽奥良确实有它的魅力
Well, as I said,
New Orleans has its charms.
但是把我召唤来
But to call me?
我可是他们眼中的毁灭者
The one they call "The Destroyer."
我曾把比这更有魅力的城市
The one who's burnt cities
far more charming
夷为平地，只为找到他的孩子
to the ground
in pursuit of his children.
但现在我明白了
But now I see.
你这么做是为了爱情，我女儿的爱
You did it for love,
the love of my daughter.
不准你碰她
Don't you dare touch her.
所以我打算给你一个承诺
So, I'm going to make you a promise.
我不会伤害蕾贝卡
I won't hurt Rebekah.
说实话，她一直是我的最爱
Truth be told,
she was always my favorite.
而这座城市，你可以拿去
And this city?
You can have it.
但首先你必须告诉我
我的儿子在哪里
But first, you must tell me
where to find my sons.
- 你还很虚弱
- 我还是很饿
-You're still weak.
-I'm still hungry.
厨房里有新鲜的血
There's a fresh blood supply
in the kitchen.
你撑不到那里去的
You won't make it that far.
所以你就乖乖地躺回床上去吧
So be a good little boy
and get back into bed.
如果每次有女人对我说这句话
我都能得到一英镑…
If I had a quid for every time
a woman has tried that line on me...
- 那你就是穷光蛋
- 恕我不敢苟同
-You'd have, like, no money.
-I beg to differ.
还是有女人觉得我很有魅力的
Some women actually find me
quite charming.
与敌人上床呢
Sleeping with the enemy, I see.
- 我现在是盟友了，亲爱的
- 确实如此
-I'm the ally now, darling.
-Well, indeed.
我们的宿敌为了示好
And as a gesture of goodwill
from our old enemy,
送了今晚歌剧“清教徒”的票
tickets to tonight's opera,
Les Huguenots.
他们有一个非常出色的女高音
They have a soprano to die for.
如果你们保证不吃了她
我就介绍你们认识
I'll introduce you
if you promise not to eat her.
拉娜
出色的女高音绝不会变成晚餐的
Oh, Lana,
a good soprano is never dinner.
叫蕾贝卡带马赛尔来
Tell Rebekah to bring Marcel.
现在就可以告诉她，哥哥
Feel free to tell her now,
big brother.
我还有事情要和我们的新盟友讨论呢
I have some business
I need to discuss with our new ally.
我怎么一点都不惊讶你喜欢歌剧？
Why am I not surprised
you like opera?
我总是特别容易为“清教徒”动容
I always had a particular soft spot
for Les Huguenots.
我喜欢那故事
I like the story.
讲述的是一段禁忌之爱
It was a tale of forbidden love.
类似“罗密欧与朱丽叶”
A Romeo and Juliet of sorts.
将要结婚的那天
On the day they are to marry,
家人和长久以来的仇恨阻止了他们
family and long-festering hatred intervene.
数千人遭屠杀
Thousands are massacred.
在最后一慕，一位父亲
甚至杀死了亲生骨肉
A father even kills his own child
in the final act.
我几乎能体会到其中的讽刺了
I can almost appreciate the irony.
来
Here.
这是研磨成糊状的草药
能够作为咒语的传导物
It's herbs ground into paste,
it'll act as a conduit for the spell.
下一次月圆，你的族人变成人类时
On the next full moon,
when your people become human,
给他们吃下，诅咒便会解除
feed it to them,
the curse will be broken.
这倒是一次毒死所有人的好方法
Great way to poison us all at once.
听着，我知道你没理由相信我
Look, I know you have no reason
to trust me.
但是，海莉，我真的很喜欢你
But, Hayley, I actually like you.
我曾像你一样
I was you.
关心以利亚
而他却更在乎他弟弟
Caring for Elijah
when he cared more for his brother.
我的下场就是死掉
And I ended up dead.
还有很多人也是
So did a lot of others.
这是一次机会，让我能够给你
因我爱得太深而无法给自己的机会
This... call it a chance
for me to give you
what I was too in love
to give myself.
是一次能够让你摆脱真祖的机会
It's a chance to free yourself
from the Originals.
你相信她吗？
You believe her?
不管她承诺你什么，都是骗你的
Whatever she's promised you,
it's a lie.
以利亚，没事，我没事
Elijah, it's okay. I'm okay.
不能相信她
She cannot be trusted.
她是唯一能够帮助我们族群的人
She's the only one
that can help my pack.
你知道她对我的家人做了什么吗？
Do you have any idea
what she has done to our family?
我知道你想复仇
I know you want revenge,
下次月圆再来吧
等我确认了她的解药有效
and come the next full moon,
when I'm sure her cure works,
她就归你了
she's all yours.
你是说我们要关着她？
Are you suggesting
that we hold her...
把她关一整个月吗？
那会需要一整支部队
Her, captive for an entire month?
-lt would take an army.
我有
-And I've got one.
要嘛帮我，要嘛不要干涉我
So help me or get out of my way.
- 你骗她
- 没有
-You tricked her.
-It's no trick.
你手里拿着的就是治愈海莉族人的解药
You're holding the cure
for Hayley's clan in your hand.
如果她的狼人们服下它，诅咒就会解除
他们就自由了
If her wolves take that elixir,
the curse is no more. They're free.
你让她的族人承受了数十年的痛苦
You condemned her people
to decades of agony,
而现在你却心甘情愿解除诅咒
and now you just break the curse
without so much as a whimper.
为什么？
Why?
因为这是我能为她做的最好的事了
Because it's the best thing
I could do for her.
也可能是我能对你做的最糟的事
And it's the worst possible thing
I could do to you.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
不论现在发生什么
你都已经失去她了
That no matter what happens now,
you've lost her.
你毁了那个罐子，杀了我
You destroy that jar, you kill me,
海莉会恨你
将她的家人从她身边夺走
Hayley will hate you
for snatching her family from her.
现在，如果你把罐子给她
Now, if you give her the jar,
我们都知道她最终也会离开你
和他们在一起
we both know that she'll leave you
in the end to be with them.
而我知道，只要她能过着
And I know
that as long as she's alive,
你无法想像的开心幸福的生活
and happy and fulfilled in ways
that you can't even imagine...
那我就复仇成功了
...then I get my revenge.
你决定吧
So, you decide.
给她想要的一切然后失去她
Give her everything she ever wanted
and lose her.
或是拒绝，看看会发生什么
Or deny it,
see what happens then.
还有一个人呢？莎宾呢？
Where's the third one?
我要求见你们三人
Sabine, I asked to meet
with all three of you.
我们见你完全是出于礼节
Our meeting you at all is a courtesy
因为你曾是女巫的朋友
for your being a friend to witches
in the past.
但礼节也是有限度的
But courtesy has its limits.
好了，你说你有我们感兴趣的消息
Now, you said you had information
of interest to us.
蕾贝卡和马赛尔回来了
Rebekah and Marcel are back.
他们为黛维娜而来
They came for Davina,
他们认为如果杀死你们三个就能救活她
and they think that they can get her
if they kill all three of you.
听着
我可以直接带你们去找他们
Now look,
I can lead you straight to them,
但我要回报
but there's something
I want in return.
是什么呢？
And what's that?
你的命
Your life.
敢跟着我，我就把你们俩烧成灰
Follow me,
and I'll turn you both into ash.
- 别管了，我们晚点再解决她
- 马赛尔
-Forget her. We'll get her later.
-Marcel.
我们仅有的优势就是出其不意
现在已经没有了
All we have is the element of surprise,
and we have lost it.
如果我们现在不离开
就没人会救我们了
If we don't leave now,
there will be no one to save us.
我已经让黛维娜失望了一次
我不会丢下她的
I already failed Davina once.
I'm not leaving her behind.
我不觉得这会有帮助
Not sure that helps.
那可不一定
Not sure it doesn't.
你想要自我治愈自怨自艾，没问题
You want to self-medicate
your self-pity, fine.
不管以利亚怎么说
喝威士忌总比喝我的血强
Better Scotch than my blood,
no matter what Elijah says.
别跟我提以利亚
Don't speak to me of Elijah.
- 他爱你
- 是的
-He loves you.
-Yes.
他是爱我，也屦次证明了这点
He does. and he proves it
time and again.
即使是在我父亲要求他杀了我时
Even when my father
enlisted him to kill me.
“清教徒”
Les Huguenots.
在威尼斯时看过，了不起的作品
Saw it in Venice,
marvelous production.
- 是你
- 没事，儿子
-You.
-It's all right, son.
我只是想聊聊
I just want to talk.
你无情地追杀了我们好几个世纪
You mercilessly hunt us for centuries.
毁掉了半个欧洲
现在你只是单纯想要聊聊？
You laid waste to half of Europe,
now you...
You simply wish to talk?
我追杀的是你那个杂种弟弟
It was your bastard brother I hunted.
不是你，从来都不是你
Not you, never you.
你是我的骨肉
是我能骄傲称之为儿子的骨肉
You're my blood,
one that I'd be proud to call son.
我来是为了给你一个机会
So, I came here to give you a chance
帮我永久解决掉那个畜生
to help me put down
that whelp for good.
你真的不了解我吗？
Do you really not know me?
你觉得我可以或者我会
相信你说的任何话吗？
You think I could or would believe
in anything that you say?
如果你真以为我会为了你背叛我弟弟
If you honestly believe
I would betray my own brother for you,
那你真是太蠢了
you're a fool without equal.
我原谅你，对你称之为弟弟的那东西
I'll forgive you
your sentimental affections
感情用事
for the thing you call brother.
但你要知道
But you need to realize, as I did,
在我得知他母亲
和一个畜生睡了之后生出了他
when I learned his mother
had lain with a beast to beget him...
尼克劳斯就是个令人厌恶的东西
...Niklaus is an abomination.
你不能和令人厌恶的东西说话
You do not talk to abominations.
不能和他们讲理
或是试图改变他们
You do not reason with them,
or try to change them.
只能除掉他们
You erase them!
是的，我要求你帮我杀死你弟弟
So, yes, I am asking you
to help me kill your brother.
你一直说杀死
You keep saying kill,
但你是永生的，你不能被杀死
but you're immortal.
You can't be killed.
可以的，亲爱的
Oh, but we can, love.
而我父亲就是唯一
有办法杀死我们的人
And my father was the only one
with the means to do it.
一根白橡树木桩
A white oak stake,
出自我父亲之手
fashioned by my father
要从我们这里夺走
他强加于我们身上的东西
to take from us the very thing
he forced upon us all:
永生
our immortality.
与我为盟
或者和他一起死
Stand with me or fall with him.
做选择吧，儿子
Choose, son.
我永远都会…
选择他
I will always choose him!
好吧
Fine.
以利亚始终心怀愧疚
Elijah has always carried guilt
for that night
那晚没能阻止我们的父亲
for not stopping our father.
我跟他说不要自责
I told him not to blame himself.
当父亲想要杀死你
他就是真的想这么做
When your father wants to kill you,
he wants to kill you.
你也不能做什么
Nothing you can do about it.
我不想做一个无所不知的人
Oh, I hate to be a know-it-all,
我妹妹和她的爱人在城里出现了
but my sister and her lover
have been spotted in town.
恐怕故事只能讲到这里了
So, story time endeth here,
I'm afraid.
那是什么？
What is that?
白橡树木桩
A white oak stake.
我的特殊版本
My own special version.
和我父亲的不同
这一根无法被摧毁
And unlike my father's,
this one cannot be destroyed.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
如果你非得问的话
If you have to ask,
就说明显然你都没专心听
you obviously
haven't been paying attention.
我要去杀我妹妹
I'm going to kill my sister.
但首先，我得吃些
马鞭草含量低的食物
But first, I needed some sustenance
with a little less vervain in it.
请勿见怪
No offense.
当黛维娜给我看了你对我所做的一切
When Davina showed me
all you did to me,
你从我这里夺走的一切时
我想杀了你
all you took from me,
I wanted to kill you.
我甚至想过把那把刀刺进你的身体
就像女巫们要求我做的那样
I even thought about burying
that blade in you,
但我没有
我停下来思考，我权衡了
Iike the witches asked me to,
but I didn't.
在你身上所看到的优点
I stopped. I thought.
I weighed the good I see in you
和我知道的你所做的可怕的事
versus the horrible things
I know you've done,
我意识到如果我伤害了你
我会满怀痛苦的悔恨
and I realized if I hurt you,
I'd be filled with a terrible regret.
你也会如此，如果你伤害你妹妹的话
她可是你妹妹，克劳斯
You will, too, if you hurt
your sister, your sister, Klaus!
身为一个失去手足
感受过那种痛楚的人
As a person who has lost a sibling,
who has felt that pain,
如果你杀了她，你会活不下去的
you won't survive
if you're the one who kills her.
我告诉你什么让我
差点活不下去吧，亲爱的
I'll tell you
what I almost didn't survive, love.
我妹妹
My sister,
bringing the most vile creature
把这地球上最邪恶的生物招来了
ever to have walked the earth
down upon me.
是的，你父亲
Yes, your father.
但追杀蕾贝卡和马赛尔到天涯海角
But by hunting Rebekah and Marcel
down to the ends of the earth,
用你曾经经历的恐怖来威吓他们
by terrorizing them the way you
yourself were terrorized...
不要变成你父亲
Don't become your father.
我已经被认为是不折不扣的恶魔
I've been called
every shade of monster,
但这倒是第一次
我父亲？
but that's new.
My father?
麦可是连恶魔都害怕的魔鬼
Mikael was the monster
monsters were afraid of.
来，我带你看看
Come. Let me show you.
- 你回来了
- 我一直都会回来的
-You came back.
-I always come back.
拿着吧
Take it.
会有用的
It will work.
我和伊芙会尽量召集族人
Eve and I will round up
as many of our people as we can.
等月圆时，我终于能解救我的家人了
Come full moon,
I can finally free my family.
海莉
Hayley.
不知道他们是否知道
拥有你是何其幸运的事
I wonder if they have any idea
how lucky they are to have you.
真感人
多么纯洁的轻吻
That was touching.
Such a chaste, little kiss.
我所认识的以利亚可绝不会如此温和
The Elijah I knew was never so meek.
我所认识的莎莉丝特绝不会这么残忍
Well, the Celeste I knew
was never so cruel.
你想要什么？你最终的目的是什么？
What is it that you want?
What's your endgame?
这场游戏永远不会结束，以利亚
Oh, this game never ends, Elijah.
我们都是永生的，你知道
We're both immortal, you know.
如果你赢不了，那还有什么意义呢？
Then what's the point
if you can't possibly win?
但我赢了啊
But I have.
你刚刚失去了那女孩
You just lost the girl.
你无法和她更进一步
The girl you never made a move on
因为你太急切地想要拯救你的家人
because you were so desperate
to save your family.
如今你的家人毁灭了
And now your family lies in ruins.
尽管你做了那些事，我的家人
My family,
despite all that you have done,
还是会完好如初的
will heal in time.
如果你们有时间的话，也许吧
If you had the time, maybe.
但你真觉得蕾贝卡飞快逃离这里了吗？
But you really think Rebekah
ran far and fast from here?
- 我敢说她没有
- 她早走了
-I bet she didn't.
-She's long gone.
是吗？
Is she?
她和马赛尔在一起
She's with Marcel.
马赛尔深爱黛维娜
黛维娜死了
Now, Marcel loves Davina.
Davina is dead.
但她可能活过来
只要条件对了
But she could come back
under the right circumstances.
你敢
They wouldn't dare.
如果你没有这么担心海莉
你也许会早点想明白
If you hadn't been so worried
about Hayley,
you might have figured
it out sooner.
但你知道谁有时间想明白吗？
But you know who did have the time
to think about it?
你弟弟
我想知道他会做出什么
Your brother.
I wonder what he'll do.
来吧
Do it.
你知道这个城市的历史吧
You know your city's history.
1919年那晚
That night in 1919,
这里的歌剧院被烧毁了
when the opera house burnt down
on this very spot?
那是我父亲的杰作
That was my father at his worst.
这可不是个好的开始
Well, this is off to a bad start.
在我给予你们祝福之后
Your first big date
together in public
你们第一次公开的重要约会
他却放你鸽子了
after I gave you my blessing,
and he stood you up.
他一定有事情耽搁了
Something must have delayed him.
或者，你们的恋情公开了
Or, now that your illicit affair
is out in the open,
他发现整段恋情乏善可陈
he finds the whole relationship
a tad lackluster
就和舞女私奔去哈瓦那了
and has run off to Havana
with a showgirl.
别这么泥蛋，我去大厅找找
Don't be such a toe rag.
I'm going to check the lobby.
顺便去看看我们的哥哥在不在
See if you can't find our brother
while you're there.
就快开始了
The curtain is about to go up.
我劝你最好不要试图逃跑，孩子
I would advise against
trying to flee, boy.
在你试图逃跑之前
I can drive this into your heart
我就能把这个刺进你的心脏
before you can even think
of getting to your feet.
我暂时还不想让你死
And I don't want you to die, yet.
- 父亲
- 父亲？
-Father.
-"Father"? (CHUCKLES)
这么多年了你还坚持用这个词？
Still clinging to that word
after all these years?
一个渴望父亲的野种？
A bastard desperate for a daddy?
不知道你的亲生父亲
在我发现你不是我亲生的之前
I wonder if your real father would be
as embarrassed as I was of you
是否像我一样因你而感到丢脸
before I discovered you were not mine.
很有可能
Most likely.
别激动，孩子
Whoa, whoa. Ah-ah.
Easy now, boy.
别担心
死亡终究会成真
Don't worry.
Death will come.
但在你摆脱永生的困扰之前
But we need to have a little chat
我们得聊一聊
before you shuffle off
your immortal coil.
我们要对彼此说的话早就说完了
Any words we have for each other
have been spoken long ago.
但你要知道
But know this.
我不再是那个
I am no longer the animal
乞求你一点点关爱的动物了
begging for scraps of your affection.
我死的时候，可以坦然恨你
I will die
knowing my hatred of you was just.
我会在我建立的城池中骄傲地死去
I will fall,
proud of all I have achieved here.
所以…
So...
麦可
Mikael,
如果你要杀我
那就赶紧动手吧
if you're going to kill me,
then get on with it.
恰恰相反，尼克劳斯
有些话还没说呢
Au contraire, Niklaus,
some things remain unsaid.
比如，你在这里的成就的确值得骄傲
For instance, you were right
to be proud of your achievement here.
当我走在街上，城里的上流人士
As I walked the streets,
your name was spoken of
提起你都毕恭毕敬
in reverent tones
by the city's finest.
在我杀了你之后
So after I kill you,
我会继续待在纽奥良
I will remain here in New Orleans
直到每一个记得你的人都死去
until every last person
who remembers you is dead.
伟大的克劳斯的功绩
再也没有人记得
The deeds of the mighty Klaus
will be remembered by no one!
而你，孩子
And you, boy...
就像从没存在过
...will simply never have existed.
盛大的演出
Ah. The grand show.
为了你，我做了一些更动
I made some alterations in your honor.
你会喜欢的
You'll love it.
那真是一出好戏
KLAUS:
And what a show it was.
麦可魅惑观众看完
Mikael had compelled the audience
to watch it all...
把它当做一出滑稽喜剧而鼓掌
...to applaud as if it were
the drollest of comedies...
然后给歌剧院留下了惊心动魄的一晚
...and then to leave celebrating
a terrific night at the opera.
我试图救下马赛尔
I tried to save Marcel.
我父亲却另有打算
My father had other ideas.
蕾贝卡试图阻止他
Rebekah attempted to intervene.
不！
No...
这些年，我真的相信她是想救我
All these years, I actually believed
she was trying to save me.
然后大哥冲了出来
But then big brother swooped in.
帮不了马赛尔了
There's no helping Marcel.
就在我们以为一切都没用了
Just when we thought all was lost.
我们得赶紧跑了
We must run.
所以我逃跑了
And so I ran,
像我父亲认为的丧家之犬一样被打败了
beaten like the dog
my father believed me to be.
在我们逃命之时
他把这里烧成平地
And as we fled for our lives,
he burnt it all to the ground...
我们以为马赛尔也烧死了
...and with it, we assumed, Marcel.
我活下来了
但我们所建立的一切都毁了
I lived,
but all that we had built died.
我最后一点人性也因此而毁
As did the last shred of me
that felt human.
这就是那晚我父亲从我身上夺走的东西
That is what my father
took from me that night.
我向你保证，卡蜜
I assure you, Cami,
我不会恐吓我妹妹和她的爱人数个世纪
I will not terrorize my sister
and her lover for centuries.
我也不会羞辱、折磨，使他们丧失人性
Nor will I humiliate,
torment or dehumanize them.
都不会
No, none of that.
我会简单快速地了结他们
I will simply and quickly end them.
克劳斯，等等
Klaus, wait.
带我来这也用不着咬我吧
Now, you didn't have to bite me
to get me here.
我想要坐前排看好戏呢
I wanted front-row seats
to this show.
什么好戏？
And what show would that be?
你即将看到你的“永远在一起”约定
The one where you see
your "always and forever" pact
毁于一旦
come crashing down around you.
那是个神话，以利亚
我渴望的神话
It's a myth, Elijah.
A myth I died for.
你现在还活着
暂时而已
And yet here you stand alive,
for now.
这是威胁吗？
Is that a threat?
总会有一个美丽的
年轻的身体等着我进入
Oh, there's always another pretty,
young body for me to jump into.
从现在开始
From now on,
每一次你对一个女人有感觉时
every time you feel
a connection to a woman,
你都会被迫先想想这会不会是我
you'll be forced to wonder
if it's me.
你不会相信任何人
You'll trust no one
独自一人度过你的永生
and spend the rest of eternity
alone.
恐怕你是被困住了
I'm afraid you're trapped.
边界咒语
真祖可以进却不能出
Boundary spell. The Originals
can enter, but they can't leave.
- 你不会这么做吧
- 我会，我也这么做了
-You wouldn't.
-I would, and I did.
我找到你了，小黛
I got you, D.
我找到你了
I got you.
这是个陷阱
快走
It's a trap. Run.
- 带着黛维娜离开这里
- 我不会丢下你的
-Get Davina out of here.
-I'm not leaving you behind.
- 你必须要
- 我不会离开你的
-You must.
-I will not leave you behind.
我发誓我会追上你的
快走，带黛维娜去安全的地方
I swear I will join you.
Go. Get Davina someplace safe.
我会的
I will.
别担心，这只是个月咒
下一次月亮升起时你就自由了
Don't worry. It's a lunar spell.
You'll be free by the next moonrise.
我猜
你妹妹撑不到那时候了
My guess is,
your sister won't last that long.
这副身体真是充满乐趣
While this body
has been a hell of a lot of fun,
我觉得该换个人玩玩了，你说呢？
I do think it's time I find someone else
to play in, don't you?
你说得对
You were right.
将此灵魂回到…
(CHANTlNG lN FORElGN LANGUAGE)
Return this soul...
你好，莎莉丝特
Hello, Celeste.
这怎么可能？
How is this possible?
我和莫妮克德弗罗打了个小赌
Monique Deveraux and l
had a little wager
关于你是否能够遵守承诺
regarding your ability
to keep a promise.
看来我赢了
It appears I won.
你一心想摧毁我
You were so consumed
with my downfall,
却失去了一位自己人的信任
that you lost the trust
of one of your own.
不
No...
亲爱的，住手
Mon cher, no.
凡事都有可能
一切还未结束
抱歉
Desole.
黛维娜，你没事了
Davina, you're okay.
你现在很安全
听见了吗？你很安全
You're safe now.
You hear me? You're safe.
我不会让任何人伤害你的
I won't let anyone hurt you, okay?
蕾贝卡！
Rebekah!
珍惜你仅剩的几口气吧
这是你最后的机会了
Cherish the breath in your lungs!
It'll be your last.
大木偶剧场的最后一幕就要开始了
The final act of Le Grand Guignol
is upon us!
我的演员呢？
跑够了，孩子们
Where are my players?
Enough running, children!
出来吧
Step out of the shadows,
我们就能结束这悲伤的故事了
so we may finish
this tale of sorrows!
- 他来了
- 好
-He's coming.
-Okay.
喝吧，妹妹
Drink, sister.
马赛尔
Marcel.
- 他死了，妹妹
- 不
-He's gone, sister.
-No!
你们俩得赶快离开这里
我来拖住他，尼克劳斯
Both of you must flee the city.
I'll hold him off, Niklaus.
不
我们一起对付他
No. We fight him together.
我们打不过他的
We cannot fight him.
我们只能像以前一样
欺骗他
All we can do is do what we've done.
We deceive him.
把他引开
我可以做到
We lead him astray.
I can do that as well as anyone.
你带着她离开
我会去找你们的
You take her far away from here.
I'll find you.
不，以利亚，不行
不行，以利亚
No, Elijah! You can't.
You can't, Elijah.
- 这…这是我的错
- 不
-This is just... This is my fault.
-No.
这是我的错，蕾贝卡
This is my fault, Rebekah.
真的对不起，对不起
I am so sorry. I'm sorry.
马赛尔…
Marcel...
我以为我们在这里找到了家
I thought we'd found a home here.
尼克劳斯，拜托
妹妹，来
Niklaus, please.
Sister, come.
你们得离开了，快走
You must leave. Go.
快走啊
Leave!
以利亚？
Elijah?
你在这做什么？
What are you doing here?
蕾贝卡，你现在应该在世界的另一头了
Rebekah, you should be
on the other side of the world by now.
你我都知道那也不够远
You and I both know
that wouldn't have been far enough.
离她远点！
Get away from her!
她是我的
She's mine.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）